Guide to the New York State College of Agriculture 4-H club records, 1918-2018.
New York State College of Agriculture 4-H club records
- Series III. 4-H Club Records
  - C. Records
    - State 4-H Advisory Committee, 1985-1989 (Box 125, Folder 3)
    - State 4-H Advisory Committee, 1989-1994 (Box 125, Folder 4)
    - Adult leadership study (Box 125, Folder 5)
    - New York State 4-H Arts in Program, 1980 (Box 125, Folder 6)
    - Career education, 1976-1978 (Box 125, Folder 7)
    - Cornell Cooperative Extension Facts and Figures, 1985 (Box 125, Folder 8)
    - Clothing construction, 1978-1984 (Box 125, Folder 9)
    - Cloverbuds, 1994 (Box 125, Folder 10)
    - Collegiate 4-H, 1980-1995 (Box 125, Folder 11)
    - 4-H community development brochure (Box 125, Folder 12)
      Undated
    - Northeast States Conference on 4-H Leadership Tenure Study, 1964 (Box 125, Folder 13)
    - 4-H clubs importance, 1975 (Box 125, Folder 14)
    - Six delivery modes; alternatives for the involvement of youth through 4-H (Box 125, Folder 16)
      1975
    - Discover 4-H, 1985-1987 (Box 125, Folder 17)
    - Discover 4-H: subject matter experiences for youth in late childhood, 1986 (Box 125, Folder 17A)
    - District 4-H leaders guides (Box 125, Folder 18)
      1969, 1971
    - Evaluation: program development, 1980-1990 (Box 125, Folder 19)
    - Family Community Leadership Institute, 1989-1990 (Box 125, Folder 20)
    - Annual reports: Cornell Cooperative Extension, 1988 (Box 125, Folder 21)
    - 5-H News, 1993-1995 (Box 125, Folder 22)
    - 5-H News, 2004-12, 2008-07, 2014-07 (Box 148, Folder 58)
    - Health education, 1976-1980 (Box 125, Folder 23)
    - Leadership Laboratories, 1972-1980 (Box 125, Folder 26)
    - Let's Explore, 1969 (Box 125, Folder 27)
    - Mountains and Men, 1974-1977 (Box 125, Folder 28)
    - Multicultural resource guide, 1993 (Box 125, Folder 29)
    - New staff orientation, 1988 (Box 125, Folder 30)
    - Delegates to Northeast Regional 4-H Volunteer Leader Forum, Columbia Maryland- Photo; Delegates to New York State Northeast Regional Leader Forum Fairlee, Vermont- Photo; Letter from Former First Lady Barbara Bush to Northeast 4-H Regional Leaders Forum in Albany, New York, 1985; 1989-10 (Box 125, Folder 31)
    - Skills gained by 4-H club presidents survey, 1987 (Box 125, Folder 32)
    - The Reporter's World; teaching kit for 4-H reporters, 1978 (Box 125, Folder 32)
    - Phyllis Stout Leadership Development Conference, 1967 (Box 125, Folder 34)
    - Priority 4-H club delivery program, 1986 (Box 125, Folder 35)
    - Position statements related to the 4-H program in New York State (Box 125, Folder 36)
      1977
    - Program initiative, 1990-1999 (Box 125, Folder 37)
    - Cornell Cooperative Extension program initiative, 1990-1999 (Box 125, Folder 38)
    - 4-H program managers conference, 1986 (Box 125, Folder 39)
    - Program priority, 1970-1979 (Box 125, Folder 40)
    - 4-H promotion, 1986-1988 (Box 125, Folder 41)
    - Public speaking, 1970 (Box 125, Folder 42)
    - Safety, 1990-1991 (Box 125, Folder 43)
    - Science and 4-H, 1963 (Box 125, Folder 44)
    - School dropouts, 1964 (Box 125, Folder 45)
    - Spanish programs, 1972-1974 (Box 125, Folder 46)
    - Strategic planning, 1994-1995 (Box 125, Folder 47)
    - Study on characteristics of 4-H leaders, 1961-1962 (Box 125, Folder 48)
    - Teen programs, 1974-1977, 1987 (Box 125, Folder 49)
    - Teenagers and 4-H: Why do they drop out? How can they be retained?, 1984; Hamilton, Stephen (Box 125, Folder 49)
    - Leadership development program for teens, 1972 (Box 125, Folder 50)
    - Evaluation 58th New York State 4-H Congress, 1984-06; Googin, Stephen (Box 125, Folder 50)
    - Youth sexuality program, 1972-1973 (Box 125, Folder 51)
    - 4-H participation data, 1986-1987 (Box 126, Folder 1)
    - 4-H participation data, 1987-1988 (Box 126, Folder 2)
    - 4-H participation data, 1988-1989 (Box 126, Folder 3)
    - 4-H participation data, 1989-1990 (Box 126, Folder 4)
    - 4-H participation data, 1990-1991 (Box 126, Folder 5)
    - 4-H participation data, 1991-1992 (Box 126, Folder 6)
    - 4-H participation data, 1992-1993 (Box 126, Folder 7)
    - 4-H participation data, 1993-1994 (Box 126, Folder 8)
    - EFNEP, 1985 (Box 127, Folder 3)
    - MM Good Try Something New Nutrition, 1977 (Box 127, Folder 4)
    - Resource books/manuals, 1943-1990 (Box 127, Folder 5)
    - 4-H justification/accountability, 1986 (Box 128, Folder 1)
    - State program needs, 1967 (Box 128, Folder 2)
    - Club work, 1960-1969 (Box 128, Folder 3)
    - 4-H statements, 1960-1969 (Box 128, Folder 4)
    - State program history, 1947-1987 (Box 128, Folder 5)
    - Science series contracts, 1995-1996 (Box 128, Folder 6)
    - Science series, 1995-1996 (Box 128, Folder 7)
    - Agricultural education, 1989-1990 (Box 128, Folder 8)
    - Moving Toward Tomorrow, 1976-1987 (Box 128, Folder 9)
    - State program documents, 1976-1986 (Box 128, Folder 10)
    - State program history, 1911-1987 (Box 128, Folder 11)
    - Reducing Risks and Increasing Capacity (Box 128, Folder 12)
    - International 4-H (Japan), 1992-1994 (Box 128, Folder 13)
    - International program review, 1986 (Box 128, Folder 14)
    - Central American Peace Scholarship, 1992-1993 (Box 128, Folder 15)
    - Program assistant applications, 1993 (Box 128, Folder 16)
    - National 4-H Council, 1989-1992 (Box 128, Folder 17)
    - National 4-H Agents Association, 1976-1991 (Box 128, Folder 18)
    - National 4-H council report to New York, 1990 (Box 128, Folder 19)
    - NAF 4-H-A, 1986-1991 (Box 128, Folder 20)
    - NAE 4-H conference, 1994 (Box 128, Folder 21)
    - National 4-H conference, 1928-1994 (Box 128, Folder 22)
    - National 4-H council grant proposals, 1991-1995 (Box 128, Folder 23)
    - National 4-H conference, 1964 (Box 128, Folder 24)
    - National award winners (Box 128, Folder 25)
    - Citizenship/Washington Focus, 1983 (Box 128, Folder 26)
    - Program proposals, 1970 (Box 129, Folder 1)
    - 4-H foundation proposals, 1970 (Box 129, Folder 2)
    - Program proposals, 1974 (Box 129, Folder 3)
    - Program proposals, 1978 (Box 129, Folder 4)
    - 4-H recognition, 1946-1959 (Box 129, Folder 5)
    - 4-H recognition, 1960-1969 (Box 129, Folder 6)
    - 4-H recognition, 1970-1994 (Box 129, Folder 7)
    - 4-H stats, 1985-1992 (Box 129, Folder 8)
    - New York State 4-H alumni association, 1988 (Box 129, Folder 10)
    - Adopt a Highway, 1992 (Box 129, Folder 11)
    - "Be Somebody" alcohol education, 1990 (Box 129, Folder 12)
    - Youth Works (Box 129, Folder 13)
    - June events, 1995 (Box 129, Folder 14)
    - 4-H club leader study, 1961 (Box 129, Folder 15)
    - New York State 4-H campaign, 1995 (Box 129, Folder 16)
    - 4-H private support handbook, 1970 (Box 129, Folder 17)
    - 4-H in Schools (Box 129, Folder 18)
    - Capital Days, 1995 (Box 129, Folder 19)
    - Capital Days- legislative resolutions, 1988,1989,1991 (Box 129, Folder 19A)
    - Legislative resolution- commemorating the 100th anniversary of 4-H youth development program, 2002 (Box 129, Folder 19A)
    - State 4-H health committee, 1940-1942 (Box 129, Folder 20)
    - Youth development resources, 1971-1986 (Box 129, Folder 21)
    - 4-H related conference proceedings, 1959-1986 (Box 129, Folder 22)
    - 4-H impact studies, 1964-1994 (Box 129, Folder 23)
    - Horse project, 1994 (Box 129, Folder 24)
    - 4-H brochure, 1997 (Box 129, Folder 25)
    - 4-H cost effectiveness, 1981 (Box 129, Folder 26)
    - New York agriculture in the classroom, 1985-1996 (Box 129, Folder 27)
    - Cloverbuds, 1994-1995 (Box 129, Folder 28)
    - New York State 4-H research, 1961-1989 (Box 129, Folder 29)
    - Meeting minutes 4-H work groups, 1964-1965 (Box 129, Folder 30)
    - History (Box 129, Folder 31)
    - 4-H task force, 1960-1969 (Box 129, Folder 32)
    - Out of county events/activities (Box 129, Folder 33)
    - New York State 4-H scholarships and awards, 1995 (Box 129, Folder 34)
    - Staff assignments, 1982 (Box 129, Folder 35)
    - 4-H statistical information, 1984-1985 (Box 129, Folder 36)
    - County annual 4-H statistical reports, 1965-1966 (Box 130, Folder 1)
    - State and county 4-H statistical data, 1943-1947 (Box 130, Folder 2)
    - Master annual 4-H enrollment reports, 1983-1993 (Box 130, Folder 3)
    - Camp forms, 1990-1993 (Box 130, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous (Demographic Trends and Their Implications for 4-H in the '80s in New York State), 1980 (Box 130, Folder 5)
    - Census correspondence- participation and enrollment, 1979; 1993 (Box 130, Folder 6)
    - General information sheet- fact sheets on 4-H youth development programs, 1988-1993 (Box 130, Folder 7)
    - Statewide reports (enrollment and participation data), 1976-1994 (Box 130, Folder 8)
    - Clowning - nutrition ("Teaching Nutrition through Clowning"), 1980 (Box 130, Folder 9)
    - National state 4-H leaders conferences, 1970-1989 (Box 130, Folder 10)
    - 4-H program leader's conference, 1980 (Box 143, Folder 33)
    - 4-H program leader's conference, 1981 (Box 143, Folder 34)
    - Use of the 4-H name and emblem, 1982 (Box 143, Folder 35)
    - 4-H program leader's conference, 1982 (Box 143, Folder 36)
    - 4-H program leader's conference, 1983 (Box 143, Folder 37)
    - 4-H program leader's conference, 1991 (Box 143, Folder 38)
    - 4-H leader's guides- "Heritage and Horizons"- home arts, home crafts (Box 130, Folder 11)
    - 4-H leader's guides- "Heritage and Horizons"- folk fun (Box 130, Folder 12)
    - 4-H leader's guides- "Heritage and Horizons"- folk lore and history, genealogy, 1975 (Box 130, Folder 13)
    - 4-H leader's guides- "Heritage and Horizons"- play and recreation, 1975 (Box 130, Folder 14)
    - 4-H leader's guides- "Heritage and Horizons"- foods, 1976 (Box 130, Folder 15)
    - 4-H leader's guides- "Heritage and Horizons"- farm practices, 1970-1989 (Box 130, Folder 16)
    - 4-H leader's guides- "Heritage and Horizons"- A neighborhood history mystery, 1980-1989 (Box 130, Folder 17)
    - 4-H leader's guides- "Heritage and Horizons"- costume and dress, 1980-1989 (Box 130, Folder 18)
    - 4-H leader's guides- "Heritage and Horizons"- changing the horizon, architecture, 1980-1989 (Box 130, Folder 19)
    - 4-H resource material- "Heritage and Horizons" - transportation, 1984 (Box 130, Folder 20)
    - 4-H leader's guides- "Heritage and Horizons"- exploring the arts, 1970-1989 (Box 130, Folder 21)
    - 4-H leader's guides- "Heritage and Horizons"- extension's commitment to people, 1976 (Box 130, Folder 22)
    - 4-H photo fun broadcast, 1971 (Box 130, Folder 23)
    - 4-H leader's guide- "Let Me Do It", 1979 (Box 130, Folder 24)
    - 4-H leader's guide- "Your Sewing Machine", 1966 (Box 130, Folder 24)
    - Youth and Leadership ("Teens Take the Lead" guides for leaders, "Urban Update"), 1970-1979 (Box 130, Folder 25)
    - Extension Past and Future ("4-H in the '70s; Cooperative Extension Week, "4-H Club Agents Story"; Future Directions for 4-H), 1950-1989 (Box 130, Folder 26)
    - 4-H leader's guides- "4-H Community Development Project", 1977 (Box 130, Folder 27)
    - 4-H leader's handbook- "Blue Sky Below My Feet", 1980-1989 (Box 130, Folder 28)
    - 4-H leader's guide- "Exploring Freshwater Fisheries", 1981 (Box 130, Folder 29)
    - 4-H leader's guide- "Grooming Horses and Ponies", 1983 (Box 130, Folder 30)
    - "How About Getting Involved in 4-H", 1985 (Box 130, Folder 31)
    - 4-H camping guide, 1995 (Box 130, Folder 32)
    - 4-H community service and community development projects- leader training program guide (Box 130, Folder 33)
    - 4-H Club Agents, 1938-1943 (Box 130, Folder 34)
    - Centennial annual 4-H conferences, 1947-1974 (Box 130, Folder 35)
    - Centennial website printouts, 2002 (Box 130, Folder 35)
    - International 4-H (World Atlas of 4-H, posters, other international material), 1963, 1970,1981 (Box 130, Folder 36)
    - Staffing model, 1980 (Box 130, Folder 38)
    - New Opportunities for Youth Working Together with 4-H and EFNEP, 1983 (Box 130, Folder 39)
    - History of 4-H, 1976, 2001 (Box 130, Folder 40)
    - Cooperative extension and boy scouts materials, 1950-1959 (Box 131)
    - Exploring the arts booklets, 1980-10 (Box 131)
    - Exploring the arts conference material, 1975-09 (Box 131)
    - Clowning and 4-H (Box 131)
    - Evaluation study for 4-H program for older youth, 1961-03 (Box 131)
    - Young Folks, 1930 (Box 131)
    - Cornell Extension Bulletin #772, 1950-03 (Box 131)
    - Cornell Extension Bulletin #109-112, 1957-03 (Box 131)
    - How to be a Modern Leader, 1954 (Box 131)
    - Handbook of Guides for Effective 4-H Club Work, 1962-01 (Box 131)
    - Report of 4-H Task Force, 1968-12 (Box 131)
    - Cornell Extension Bulletin #993, 1957-12 (Box 131)
    - Cornell Extension Bulletin #1015, 1958-09 (Box 131)
    - Early Development of Cooperative Extension Work in Agriculture and Home Economics in the United States, 1962-07 (Box 131)
    - The Beginning of Extension Programs and Their Development Through Local Leadership, 1932-1954 (Box 131)
    - Extension Organization and Leadership Development, 1932-1954 (Box 131)
    - The Evolution of Home Economics Extension Work in the United States, 1932-1954 (Box 131)
    - The Extension Service Partnership with County Supporting Agencies in New York, 1911-1961 (Box 131)
    - The Agricultural Extension Campaign Method as Developed in New York State, 1932-1954 (Box 131)
    - Early forms of Extension Work in Agriculture and Home Economics, 1932-1954 (Box 131)
    - The Relation of the Extension Service to Farm Organizations and Commercial Enterprises, March 1963 (Box 131)
    - Operation Advance Scrapbook, 1960-1969 (Box 131)
    - The Evolution of 4-H Club Work in the United States, 1964-02 (Box 131)
    - The Federal Action Programs and Extension's Role in Their Development, 1963-10 (Box 131)
    - New York State congress programs, 1960-1979 (Box 131)
    - Operation Advance folder, 1960-1961 (Box 131)
    - Miscellaneous letters and newspaper clippings, 1960-1969 (Box 131)
    - Operation Advance community reference book and letters, 1960 (Box 131)
    - Operation Advance discussion sheet No. 1-No.3, 1963 (Box 131)
    - County Extension Service Handbook for Operation Advance, 1961, 1962 (Box 131)
    - Operation Advance discussion sheet kit, 1965-1966 (Box 131)
    - Operation Advance press and radio and television kit, 1963-1964 (Box 131)
    - Operation Advance aids for working with organizations, 1963 (Box 131)
    - Operation Advance stage 2 envelope (Box 131)
    - Operation Advance discussion sheet kit, 1964-02 (Box 131)
    - Communication aids: written communication newswritings, miscellaneous media relations, oral communication (loose papers), 1960-1969 (Box 132)
    - CA vision reference materials, 1968-1973 (Box 132)
    - 4-H ambassador notebook originals, 1988 (Box 132)
    - 4-H program update, 1978 (Box 132)
    - Management materials form In-depth, 1978 (Box 132)
    - 4-H educational activities guide, 1968 (Box 132)
    - 4-H in Century III: program directions in 4-H, 1976-1986 (Box 143, Folder 41)
    - 4-H in Century III: costing and revisions, 1979 (Box 132)
    - Financial summary 4-H club department folders for each year, 1949-1952 (Box 132)
    - Core subject matter programing, 1981 (Box 132)
    - Cornell Cooperative Extension 4-H programming workshop draft, 1988 (Box 132)
    - Staffing for Cornell Cooperative Extension 4-H youth development, 1988 (Box 132)
    - State volunteer leader newsletter "Leading Edge", 1988 (Box 132)
    - Moving Toward Tomorrow, 1986 (Box 132)
    - Tips on Working with Children in Groups, 1987 (Box 132)
    - Program resource guide, 1984 (Box 132)
    - New York State 4-H program/project resource guide for agents, 1988 (Box 143, Folder 42)
    - 4-H Ambassadors- advisor's guide book, 1980 (Box 132)
    - 4-H budget explanations, 1984-10-1988-09 (Box 132)
    - 4-H field operations, 1985-01,1985-12 (Box 132)
    - Volunteers for the Future- final report, 1989-02 (Box 143, Folder 43)
    - Applying the Youth-Driven Model in the 4-H Setting, 1997 (Box 143, Folder 44)
    - Exploring the arts program applications, 1974-03 (Box 132)
    - Exploring the arts program grant application, 1979-11 (Box 132)
    - 4-H art pamphlets and guides, 1970 (Box 132)
    - New York 4-H expressive arts guidelines, 1970-1979 (Box 132)
    - 4-H arts and crafts manuals, 1967, 1969, 1972,1973, 1975 (Box 132)
    - Touch With Your Eyes, 1980 (Box 132)
    - Exploring Your Ideas in Art, 1981 (Box 132)
    - International farm youth exchange applications, 1949-1969 (Box 132)
    - International farm youth exchange delegates- hosts packet, 1940-1969 (Box 132)
    - National workshop program reviews (old newspaper cut-outs), 1970-1979 (Box 132)
    - Involvement report on 4-H youth program, 1974-10 (Box 132)
    - Alternatives for the Involvement of Youth Through 4-H, 1975-02 (Box 132)
    - Urban 4-H workshops, 1971-1977 (Box 130, Folder 37)
    - Urban 4-H program guidelines/workshops, 1970-1979 (Box 132)
    - Urban 4-H workshop follow up, 1979-12 (Box 132)
    - Urban 4-H accomplishments, 1973-1978 (Box 143, Folder 27)
    - Appropriation of urban 4-H funds to cities, 1977 (Box 143, Folder 31)
    - Expansion of urban 4-H youth programs- New York State (Box 143, Folder 39)
    - 4-H Comes to New York City, 1971-1972 (Box 143, Folder 40)
    - Appointments and resignations- county agents, 1920-1939 (Box 146, Folder 23)
    - Appointments and resignations- county agents, 1940-1946 (Box 146, Folder 24)
    - Appointments and resignations- county agents, 1946-09-01-1951-03-31 (Box 146, Folder 25)
    - Appointments and resignations- county agents, 1951-04-01-1956-06-30 (Box 146, Folder 26)
    - Appointments and resignations- county agents, 1956-07-01-1959-12-31 (Box 146, Folder 27)
    - Appointments and resignations- county agents, 1960-01-01-1963-12-31 (Box 146, Folder 28)
    - Scholarship and loans, 1948-1971 (Box 146, Folder 29)
    - Scholarships for children of 4-H club agents, 1961-1971 (Box 146, Folder 30)
    - Western New York meat animal show- programs, 1988-2010 (Box 146, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence concerning volunteer awards, state fair program, coordinators responses from 2013 national survey, 1987-2013 (Box 148, Folder 24)
    - 4-H club secretary's handbook, 1997 (Box 148, Folder 25)
    - 4-H Icosahedron Challenge, 1999-2001 (Box 148, Folder 26)
      iincludes photographs
    - 4-H Tech Wizards, 2000-2010 (Box 148, Folder 27)
    - PowerPoints about 4-H branding, 2000-2001 (Box 148, Folder 28)
    - 4-H and the New York State Fair articles, memos, and photographs, 2001-2014 (Box 148, Folder 29)
    - Scott Peter's speech "Both the Corn and the Boy: Renewing the Civic Mission and Aims of Extension Work", 2001-05-02 (Box 148, Folder 55)
    - Youth Development Basics Workshop, 2002 (Box 148, Folder 30)
      created by the New York State Advancing Youth Development Partnership
    - Notes from videoconference "Building a Brand for 4-H Youth Development in New York State", 2004 (Box 148, Folder 31)
    - 4-H youth on The Saturday Early Show, 2002 (Box 148, Folder 32)
    - Certificate of Authority from the Department of Taxation and Finance, 2005 (Box 148, Folder 33)
    - Certificate of Liability Insurance, 2003-2010 (Box 148, Folder 33)
    - Cornell Cooperative Extension Week, 2005-10 (Box 148, Folder 34)
    - 4-H Tractor Operator's Contest, 2008-2009 (Box 148, Folder 35)
    - 4-H national safe tractor and machinery operation program, 2005; CD-5005
    - 4-H memos, worksheets, PowerPoint, 2009-2014 (Box 148, Folder 36)
    - Filmmaking workshop, 2009 (Box 148, Folder 37)
    - 4-H treasurer's record book and financial reporting guidelines, Undated (Box 148, Folder 38)
    - Agricultural Bioenergy and Bioproducts Education Workshop, 2012-12-18 (Box 148, Folder 39)
    - 4-H volunteer leaders training, recruitment and retention, 2012-2014 (Box 148, Folder 40)
    - 4-H Strong Leadership Survey, 2013-07-2013-08 (Box 148, Folder 41)
    - Land Grant Reconsidered: Invitation to a Conversation, 2013-04-16 (Box 148, Folder 42)
    - IRB approval, 2014-2017 (Box 148, Folder 43)
    - John Quinn's Farm and Farm Bureau information collected for Cornell Cooperative Extension Centennial, 2011 (Box 148, Folder 44)
  - D. County Programs/Records
    - Study of 4-H local Leadership- St. Lawrence County, 1939-08 (Box 132)
    - Homemaking Program- Onondaga County, 1941-1942 (Box 143, Folder 17)
    - Chenango County 4-H articles and memoir, 1928-1956 (Box 148, Folder 45)
      pertaining to Almstedt, Mildred
    - National 4-H Club Congress in Chicago program, photo of New York State delegates, article from Chenango County 4-H News, 1928-12 (Box 148, Folder 46)
      belonging to Almstedt, Mildred
    - Photograph of Seventh International 4-H Leaders Training School in Springfiled, MA., 1929-09 (Box 148, Folder 47)
      Includes Almstedt, Mildred
    - Chenango County 4-H Club photo with people identified, 1930-1935 (Box 148, Folder 48)
      Includes Rozelle, Mildred Almstedt
    - Agricultural College Hour radio broadcast transcript of Mildred Almstedt explaining her 4-H activities, 1932-03-05 (Box 148, Folder 49)
    - 4-H club radio program, 1933-06-03 (Box 148, Folder 49)
    - Letter from Dick Rozelle explaining donation of his mother's 4-H material, 1999-06-15 (Box 148, Folder 50)
      Includes 1935 photograph of Mildred Almstedt and Dick Rozelle Sr.
    - 4-H in Smithville Flats and Chenango County during World War II, 1943-1945 (Box 145, Folder 3)
      by Margaret Redmond
    - Advanced seminar for 4-H leaders- Chemung County, 1966 (Box 127, Folder 1)
    - Articles about various 4-H programs throughout the state, 1970-1981 (Box 145, Folder 4-5)
    - 4-H educational activities guide, 1977 (Box 145, Folder 6-8)
    - County programs, 1973 (Box 127, Folder 2)
    - 4-H Programming- Chemung, St. Lawrence, Schuyler, Tompkins Counties, 1976-1977 (Box 143, Folder 28)
    - 4-H urban program- Broome County, 1976-1978 (Box 143, Folder 29)
    - Broome County brochures, 2007; CD-3858
    - 4-H youth development- Albany County, 1977 (Box 143, Folder 30)
    - Orange County brochures and information flyers, 2006-06; CD-3859
    - Warren County STARR, 2010; CD-3860
    - 4-H agricultural engineering projects- guidelines for county contests, 1994, 1997 (Box 143, Folder 47)
    - Building 4-H Clubs- Volume I, 1980-1989 (Box 143, Folder 48-49)
    - Building 4-H Clubs- Volume II, 1980-1989 (Box 143, Folder 50-51)
    - The Basics of Starting 4-H Clubs, 2004; CD-3905
    - 4-H geospatial workshop, 2009-06-16-2009-06-18; CD-3862
    - 4-H robotics resources, 2010-2011; CD-3902-3903
    - Jefferson County 4-H Camp Wabasso, 2013-07-21-2013-07-26; DVD-3336
      New York State Operation: military kids
- Series IV. Newsletters and other Publications
  - History and Evolution of 4-H Work, 1905-1963 (Box 118)
  - 4-H Club Agents Story, 1919-1956 (Box 118)
  - Publication- Junior Extension Work- "The Four-H Story", 1920-1929 (Box 135, Folder 122)
  - 4-H Home Garden Diary, 1939 (Box 145, Folder 9)
    Junior Extension Bulletin supplement
  - 4-H club homemaking record forms for clothing and textiles, Undated (Box 145, Folder 9)
  - Scope Newsletter, 1976-03 (Box 132)
  - Scope Newsletter, 1976-03 (Box 132)
  - 4-H Newsletter #63, 1975-06 (Box 133)
  - 4-H Newsletter #64, 1975-05 (Box 133)
  - 4-H Newsletter #62, 1975-04 (Box 133)
  - 4-H Newsletter #61, 1975-03 (Box 133)
  - 4-H Newsletter #60, 1975-02 (Box 133)
  - 4-H Newsletter #59, 1975-01 (Box 133)
  - 4-H Newsletter #58, 1974-12 (Box 133)
  - 4-H Newsletter #57, 1974-10 (Box 133)
  - 4-H Newsletter #56, 1974-09 (Box 133)
  - 4-H Newsletter #55, 1974-08 (Box 133)
  - 4-H Newsletter #53, 1974-07 (Box 133)